Garrett Hudson

garrett.hudson46@gmail.com | (919) 606-6599 | Raleigh, NC 27587

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/garretthudson46 | GitHub: github.com/ghudson46 | Portfolio: www.garretthudson.com

Summary

Dedicated and efficient full stack developer with a background in marketing and professional football and a passion for continual learning and improvement. Fully certified in a plethora of front end and back end technologies. Specializing in java and python. Recognized as a proactive, resourceful, and persistent problem-solver. Excellent communicator with effective client relationship building skills.

Experience

Front-End Web Developer (internship)
Tribal III Inc. [September 2020– Present]

- Learned and utilized react.js and AWS to contribute to the Tribal III app.
- Wrote maintainable and extensible code in a team environment.

Social Media Manager

Heritage Payment Solutions [December 2019–Present]

- Duties include content creation, posting, and maintaining the company's Instagram, twitter, and Facebook accounts
- Utilize google ads and google analytics to generate leads and observe the effectiveness of the ads and web page

Assistant Project Manager

Capitol City Homes [July 2019-December 2019]

- Responsible for the coordination and supervision of residential construction
- Managed schedule from permit to closing, scheduled vendors and subcontractors, met with inspectors, and oriented buyers with their new home

Professional Football Player (Tight End)

New York Jets, Detroit Lions, Washington Redskins, Atlanta Legends (AAF), New York Guardians (XFL) [April 2018 – February 2020]

- Played 3 professional seasons in the NFL, XFL, and AAF
- Appeared in 4 games for the Washington Redskins in 2018, making 1 catch vs the Baltimore Ravens
- Retired in February 2020 after a career ending wrist injury

Education

Oracle Junior Training Certificate Program [October 2020 – December 2020]

- Topics included Core Java, SQL, Servlet, and REST
- Committed 40 hours per week to learning and applying the material in a group setting

University of North Carolina [June 2020 – December 2020]

- Certificate in full-stack web development
- 4.0 GPA

University of Richmond [January 2015 - December 2017]

- Bachelor of Science in Business Administration (Marketing)
- 3.01 GPA

Skills

- HTML5
- CSS3
- BootStrap
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- Node.js
- Express.js
- Java
- React
- Python
- mySQL
- Git Bash/Terminal

Projects

- Pawsibilities https://cptspooky.github.io/Pawsibility/
 - Pawsibilities is a web application designed to search for pets that need a home, and give the user their information and location so they can be adopted.
 - This project was worked on as a group. We used HTML, CSS, bootstrap, JavaScript, and jQuery, as well as pet finder API and map box API.
 - I was responsible for writing the script for the search form, storing input in the local storage, and generating the map, marker
 - and popup to show the animal's location.
- RateFlix https://ghudson46.github.io/rateflix
 - I created rateflix as a personal application to get quick information on various movies. I used ajax to call the omdd api and render html to give me the title, movie poster, release year, director, cast, run time, and rotten tomatoes score.
 - For this project I used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and OMDB api.
- Weather Dashboard https://ahudson46.aithub.io/weather-forecast/
 - This weather dashboard is a web application designed to take a city, inputted by the user, and show the current weather in that city. The dashboard also shows the user the forecast over the
 - city. The dashboard also shows the user the forecast over the next 5 days for that city, Cities are saved in local storage after they

- are searched, and can be easily clicked in the future to quickly bring up weather data.
- For this project I used HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, and the open weather API

Awards and Achievements

Academic

 Selected to the CAA academic all-conference team in 2016 and 2017

Athletic

- 1st team All-CAA Tight End in 2016 and 2017
- Pre-season All-American in 2017
- Set University of Richmond single-season and career records for receiving yards and touchdowns by a Tight End
- Selected to play in the NFLPA Collegiate Bowl in 2017